<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on eye Bioinformatician</title>
    <link>/./post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on eye Bioinformatician</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/./post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Plot 9: The venerable box plot</title>
      <link>/./post/lets-plot-box-plot-fancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/lets-plot-box-plot-fancy/</guid>
      <description>Intro Load packages Import TSV (tab-separated-value) file Plotting! Hmm, the order is not ideal Overlay points Wilcox test ggbeeswarm Themes Themes, with some tweaking of color and text dabest, one comparison dabest, multiple comparisons Conclusion Session Info   Intro This is the 9th Let’s Plot…and I’ve not done a workup of the most useful plot - the boxplot. Oops. Well let’s rectify that.
 Load packages Many many packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Plot 8: (Animated) US State Covid-19 Case Count</title>
      <link>/./post/lets-plot-covid19-animated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/lets-plot-covid19-animated/</guid>
      <description>Load packages, pull data 2020 03 30 Update  Plotter function Cases by state Cases, with log10 scaling  Deaths by state (log10 scaled) Deaths by state, animated Shift plot Transform Data and plot Add exponential lines   Load packages, pull data 2020 03 30 Update CSSE changed their data structure, so I’ve updated the document.
I was using their “time series” data, but they dropped the US-specific (with state by state info) documents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Plot 7: Clustered Dot Plots in the ggverse</title>
      <link>/./post/lets-plot-scrna-dotplots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/lets-plot-scrna-dotplots/</guid>
      <description>2020 03 23 Update Intro Example dotplot  How do I make a dotplot? But let’s do this ourself! Dotplot! Zero effort Remove dots where there is zero (or near zero expression) Better color, better theme, rotate x axis labels Tweak color scaling  Now what? Hey look: ggtree Let’s glue them together with cowplot How do we do better? Two more tweak options if you are having trouble: One more adjust Moonshot  Downside Exercises for the reader OLD Solution (kept for posterity)   2020 03 23 Update Ming Tang pointed out a better way to align plots, so I have rewritten the back end of this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seurat FindMarker with Cluster N vs M</title>
      <link>/./post/parallel-seurat-findmarker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/parallel-seurat-findmarker/</guid>
      <description>What Easy cluster by cluster Seurat FindMarkers implementation
 Why Because Seurat’s FindMarkers (which can be parallelized if you also load library(Future) and plan(&amp;quot;multiprocess&amp;quot;)) runs with cluster N against all other clusters.
People kept asking me for “well what about cluster 23 vs 17” and I kept saying “uh, I haven’t run that because…”
 How This is being done a Mac. This may not work on a PC. Multicore stuffs are complicated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 11 09 GI2019 Personal and Medical Genomics</title>
      <link>/./post/gi2019-day04-morning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/gi2019-day04-morning/</guid>
      <description>Day 4 - Session 9 - PERSONAL AND MEDICAL GENOMICS Characterization of prevalence and health consequences of uniparental disomy in four million individuals from the general population Sub-continental ancestry inference based on the gnomAD dataset accurately classifies patients at NCH Patient stratification in the UK’s 100k Genomes Project—Using WGS and machine learning to predict cancer outcomes Inferring clone- and haplotype-specific chromosomal organization in rearranged cancer genomes with multiple sequencing technologies Identification and interpretation of common and rare variants in relation to rare disease phenotype and outcome Somatic mutation status prediction by a splicing-alteration-based machine learning technique Beyond accessibility—ATAC-seq footprinting analysis reveals dynamics of transcription factor binding during preimplantation development   Day 4 - Session 9 - PERSONAL AND MEDICAL GENOMICS  Characterization of prevalence and health consequences of uniparental disomy in four million individuals from the general population Priyanka Nakka, Samuel Pattillo Smith, Anne H.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GI2019 2019 11 08 Afternoon Session</title>
      <link>/./post/gi2019-day03-afternoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/gi2019-day03-afternoon/</guid>
      <description>Day 3 - Session 8 - EVOLUTION AND PHYLOGENETICS Is pathogen evolution predictable? The role of population genomics Learning the properties of adaptive regions with functional data analysis Creating pan-human and population-specific consensus representations of the reference genome and assessing their effect on functional genomic data analysis Gramene subsites—Pangenome browsers for crops  What do we gain when tolerating loss? The information bottleneck, lossy compression, and detecting horizontal gene transfer A recurrent neural network for inferring sweeps and allele frequency trajectories using gene trees based on the ancestral recombination graph Assembling the Y chromosomes of anopheles mosquitoes   Day 3 - Session 8 - EVOLUTION AND PHYLOGENETICS Genome Informatics 2019 at CSHL</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GI2019 2019 11 08 Morning Session</title>
      <link>/./post/gi2019-day03-morning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/gi2019-day03-morning/</guid>
      <description>Day 3 - Session 7 - MICROBIAL AND METAGENOMICS Strain-level metagenomic assignment and compositional estimation for long reads with MetaMaps metaFlye—Scalable long-read metagenome assembly using repeat graphs Detecting microbial transmission and engraftment after faecal microbiota transplants using long-read metagenomics and reticulatus Entropy of a bacterial stress response is a generalizable predictor for fitness and antibiotic sensitivity The use of kmer counts to train random forests to predict country of origin for bacterial pathogen sequencing data Real-time assembly using Nanopore sequencing data for microbial communities Exploring the role of ribosomal gene repeats in the context of regeneration Genomic epidemiology of West Nile virus in California   Day 3 - Session 7 - MICROBIAL AND METAGENOMICS Genome Informatics 2019 at CSHL</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GI2019 2019 11 07</title>
      <link>/./post/gi2019-day02/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/gi2019-day02/</guid>
      <description>Day 2 - Session 2 - SEQUENCING ALGORITHMS, VARIANT DISCOVERY AND GENOME ASSEMBLY Genomic sketching with HyperLogLog centroFlye—Assembling centromeres with long error-prone reads Genotyping structural variants in pangenome graphs using the vg toolkit Rapidly mapping raw nanopore signal with UNCALLED to enable real-time targeted sequencing The construct and utility of reference pan-genome graphs PRINCESS — A framework for comprehensive detection and phasing of SNPs and structural variants Efficient chromosome-scale haplotype-resolved assembly of human individuals Utilization of an ensemble approach for identification of driver fusions in pediatric cancer   Day 2 - Session 2 - SEQUENCING ALGORITHMS, VARIANT DISCOVERY AND GENOME ASSEMBLY Genome Informatics 2019 at CSHL</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GI2019 2019 11 07 Night Session</title>
      <link>/./post/gi2019-day02-night/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/gi2019-day02-night/</guid>
      <description>Day 2 - Session 6 - TRANSCRIPTOMICS The functional iso-transcriptomics analysis framework to assess the functional impact of alternative isoform usage Multi-resolution, interactive, atlas-scale integration of single-cell assays and experiments Efficient and robust transcriptome reconstruction from long-read RNA-seq alignments Deconvolving the pervasive transcription from jumping genes in RNA-seq and unveiling their role in tumors Alignment and mapping methodology influence transcript abundance estimation A technology-agnostic long-read analysis pipeline for transcriptome discovery and quantification Quantifying isoform expression in single-cell RNA-seq data with STARsolo-Quant Full-length transcript characterization for single cell RNA-seq analysis   Day 2 - Session 6 - TRANSCRIPTOMICS Genome Informatics 2019 at CSHL</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GI2019 2019 11 06</title>
      <link>/./post/gi2019-day01/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/gi2019-day01/</guid>
      <description>Day 1 - Session 1 - GENOME STRUCTURE AND FUNCTION Comparative 3D genome organization in Apicomplexan parasites Unscrambling the tumor genome via integrated analysis of structural variation and copy number Tissue-specific enhancer functional networks for associating distal regulatory regions to disease Targeted Nanopore sequencing with Cas9 for studies of methylation, structural variants, and mutations Long-read sequencing of structurally variant genomes Exploring the 3D spatial dependency of gene expression using Markov random fields Mapping cis-eQTL from RNA-seq data with no genotypes Exploring short tandem repeat expansions at both known and novel loci in the human genome    Day 1 - Session 1 - GENOME STRUCTURE AND FUNCTION Genome Informatics 2019 at CSHL</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Developer Portal: eyeIntegration Genesis</title>
      <link>/./post/one-developer-portal-genesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/one-developer-portal-genesis/</guid>
      <description>News! eyeIntegration version 1.0 went live early this year (2019-01-16) and recently was accepted for publication in IOVS. In celebration of the news, I’m posting a small series of posts about the genesis, development, upgrades, and future of eyeIntegration.
You can find our latest manuscript on bioRxiv. The latest update should go live soon.
 Background eyeIntegration was developed to serve as a quick and easy to use normal gene expression portal in eye tissues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Developer Portal: eyeIntegration Web Optimization</title>
      <link>/./post/one-developer-portal-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/one-developer-portal-optimization/</guid>
      <description>This post is a continuation from here.
Really important stuff I learned to make a performant web site in Shiny After a few months of tinkering I had a working web app on my local computer, which is a 32GB of RAM, 1TB SSD Mac Pro trashcan. All of the data objects were .Rdata, which were load() when the site was initialized. This was fine in the beginning and in fact the shiny site was deployed with this structure in May of 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GI2018 - Day Four</title>
      <link>/./post/gi2018-day-four/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/gi2018-day-four/</guid>
      <description>Variant Discovery and Genome Assembly Melissa Wilson Sayres  Prithika Sritharan (Dicks) Zemin Ning (Durbin)   Variant Discovery and Genome Assembly Melissa Wilson Sayres Sex Differences in Reference Genome Affect Variant Calling and Differential Expression
X and Y homology dotplot
 a few regions of alignment (PAR)  @sexchrlab
doi.org/10.1101/346940
 https://www.biorxiv.org/content/early/2018/07/18/346940 preprint on correct tech biases on sex chr in NGS data infer sex chromosome complement pointing out regions on autosomes with sex chr - like alignment  which is screwing up read balance which presumably could influence variant calling   chrY var calls will have many errors</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GI2018 - Day Three</title>
      <link>/./post/gi2018-day-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/gi2018-day-three/</guid>
      <description>Day 3 Rafael Irizarry Keynote Session 4: Transcriptomics, Alternative Splicing and Gene Predictions Mark Robinson (Robinson) Hagen Tilgner (Tilgner) Nikka Keivanfar (Church, 10X) Koen Van den Berge (Clement) Barbara Englehardt (Englehardt) Jeff Gaither (White) Fiona Dick (Tzoulis)  Epigenetics and non-coding genome Jordana Bell (Bell) Wouter Meuleman (Stamatoyannopoulos) Maša Roller (Flicek) Alexander Suh (Suh) Raquel Garcia-Perez (Juan)    Day 3 Very sparse and poorly written notes covering #GI2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GI2018 - Day Two</title>
      <link>/./post/gi2018-day-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/gi2018-day-two/</guid>
      <description>Day Two Personal and Medical Genomics Katie Pollard Keynote Sri Kosuri (Kosuri) Patrick Brennan (Nationwide Children’s) Kaitlin Samocha (Hurles) Tracy Ballinger (Semple) Lucia Spangenberg (Naya)  Comparative, Evolutionary, Metagenomics Ellen Leffler (Kwiatkowski) Luca Penso-Dolfin (Di Palma) Mario Caccamo (NIAB) Carla Cummins (Flicek)    Day Two  Personal and Medical Genomics Very sparse and poorly written notes covering #GI2018.
Typos everywhere. Things may change dramatically over time as I scan back through notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GI2018 - Day One</title>
      <link>/./post/gi2018-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/gi2018-day-one/</guid>
      <description>Intro 2018-09-17 Sarah Teichmann (Teichmann Lab) Girgio Gonnella (Stefan Kurtz) Luke Zappia (Oshlack?) Laura Huerta (Papatheodorou) Casey Greene (Greene) Sergei Yakneen   Intro Very sparse and poorly written notes covering #GI2018.
Typos everywhere. Things may change dramatically over time as I scan back through notes.
I’ve tried to respect #notwitter. Will be updated periodically.
Speaker (Lab | Group)
BOLDED is voice
 2018-09-17  Sarah Teichmann (Teichmann Lab) Cell Atlas Technologies and the Maternal-Fetal Interface</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Guide to Gene Name Conversion</title>
      <link>/./post/quick-guide-to-gene-name-conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/quick-guide-to-gene-name-conversion/</guid>
      <description>Background There are several popular naming systems for (human) genes:
RefSeq (NM_000350) Ensembl (ENSG00000198691) HGNC Symbol (ABCA4) Entrez (24)  Given enough time in #bioinformatics, you will have to do every possible combination of conversions.
This post will very briefly explain the most expedient way to automatically convert between these formats with R.
 More exhaustive resources http://crazyhottommy.blogspot.com/2014/09/converting-gene-ids-using-bioconductor.html
https://davetang.org/muse/2013/11/25/thoughts-converting-gene-identifiers/
 Ensembl &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; HGNC &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; Entrez Stephen Turner has built a small set of data frames (well, tibbles) with core information, including transcript &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; gene info.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#BoG18: Talk Notes</title>
      <link>/./post/bog18-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/bog18-notes/</guid>
      <description>Intro Genome Engineering and Genome Editing (Tuesday Night) Jef Boeke Writing Genomes “dark matter” big dna  Greg Findlay (Jay Shendure) Stephen Levene (Andrew Fire) David Truong (Jef Boeke) Feng Zhang Molly Gasperini (Jay Shendure) Eilon Sharon (Hunter Fraser) Luca Pinello  Population Genomics (Wednesday morning) Mattias Joakobsson Jaemin Kim (Elaine Ostrander) Ipsita Agarwal (Molly Przeworski) Amnon Koren Sarah Tishkoff Patrick Albers (Gil McVean) Laura Hayward (Guy Sella)  Functional Genetics and Epigenomics Job Dekker Flora Vaccarino Carninci Johnathan Griffiths (Berthold Gottgens) Emma Farley Jake Yeung (Felix Naef) Minal Caliskan (Casey Brown) Parisa Razaz (Talkwoski)  Evolutionary and Non-human genomics Monica Justice Arang Rhie (Erich Jarvis, Adam Phillippy) Olga Dudchenko (Erez Lieberman Aiden) Kasper Munch Gavin Sherlock Anne Ruxandra Carvunis Elaine Ostrander Bobbie Cansdale (Claire Wade)  Cancer and Medical Genomics Trey Ideker Rajbir Batra (Carlos Caldas) Patrick Short (Matthew Hurles) Max Shen (David Gifford) Sharon Plon (PJ Lupo) Massa Shoura (Andrew Fire) Sidi Chen Marcin Imielinski  Computational Genomics (!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Plot 6: Simple guide to heatmaps with ComplexHeatmaps</title>
      <link>/./post/simple-heatmaps-with-complexheatmaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/simple-heatmaps-with-complexheatmaps/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Data processing Load data Peek at expression Peek at metadata Brief outline on how the RNA-seq data was processed before we see it Load libraries Create a Sample - Sample distance heatmap Easy heatmap with ComplexHeatmap Complex heatmap Finished heatmap  Gene Heatmaps A bit simpler  Session Info   Introduction Heatmaps are a core competency for a bioinformatician. They are a compact way to visually demonstrate relationships and changes in values across conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Template for rmarkdown reports</title>
      <link>/./post/template-for-rmarkdown-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/template-for-rmarkdown-reports/</guid>
      <description>What is this? Since I keep opening up random recent Rmarkdown documents to copy the header to paste into my next document, I figure it would be more efficient to just make a post I could reach from anywhere (with an internet connection).
 Copy / paste: --- title: THE TITLE author: David McGaughey date: &amp;#39;`r format(Sys.Date(), &amp;quot;%Y-%m-%d&amp;quot;)`&amp;#39; output: html_notebook: theme: flatly toc: true code_folding: hide --- ```{r, message=F, warning=F, include=F} # Load Libraries without printing any warnings or messages library(tidyverse) ``` # Session Info</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy bam downsampling</title>
      <link>/./post/easy-bam-downsampling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/easy-bam-downsampling/</guid>
      <description>When you have a set of ChIP-seq (like) files, it is sometimes useful to downsample the larger samples to more closely match most of the samples. Tommy Tang goes into more detail in his blog post.
Unfortunately the tool suites I use most for bam files (samtools and picard) only downsample to a percentage. Which isn’t ideal when you want your files to be no more than n reads.
This post is just a slight one-upping of Tommy Tang’s process to easily downsample a bam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Plot 5: ridgeline density plots</title>
      <link>/./post/let-s-plot-5-ridgeline-density-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/let-s-plot-5-ridgeline-density-plots/</guid>
      <description>Intro For this installment of Let’s Plot (where anyone can make a figure!), we’ll be making the hottest visualization of 2017 - the joy plot or ridgeline plot.
Joy plots are partially overlapping density line plots. They are useful for densely showing changes in many distributions over time / condition / etc.
This type of visualization was inspired by the cover art from Joy Division’s album Unknown Pleasures and implemented in the R package ggridges by Claus Wilke.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are you in genomics and building models? Stop using ROC - use PR</title>
      <link>/./post/are-you-in-genomics-stop-using-roc-use-pr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/are-you-in-genomics-stop-using-roc-use-pr/</guid>
      <description>tldr Area Under the Curve (AUC) of Receiver Operating Characteristic (ROC) is a terrible metric for a genomics problem. Do not use it. This metric also goes by AUC or AUROC. Use Precision Recall AUC.
 Inspiration for this post I am working on a machine learning problem in genomics I was getting really confused why AUROC was so worthless scienceTwitter featuring Anshul Kundaje  I want to save you (some time)   What’s a ROC?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Something Different: Automated Neighborhood Traffic Monitoring</title>
      <link>/./post/traffic-monitoring-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/traffic-monitoring-intro/</guid>
      <description>title: ‘Something Different: Automated Neighborhood Traffic Monitoring’ author: David McGaughey date: ‘2018-03-03’ slug: traffic-monitoring-intro categories: - R - python - raspberry - pi tags: - R - python - raspberry - pi —
Introduction This is, obviously, a personal project. Traffic is a concern in my town. Cut-through, speeding, etc. The town has paid for a couple of (very expensive!) traffic surveys, but the reports are not very useful as the company only sets up in town for a few days (if that) and then only reports stuff like ‘number of cars for a one hour period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Plot 4: R vs Excel, Round 1</title>
      <link>/./post/let-s-plot-4-r-vs-excel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/let-s-plot-4-r-vs-excel/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Data Cleaning Reformatting Box Plot Boxplot with all the data displayed I used to prefer violin plots I’m a fan of beeswarm plots with boxplots Doing statistics. Session   Introduction The battle that we’ve all been waiting for. Excel vs. R. Bar plot versus a plot that actually shows the data.
Yeah, this isn’t a fair fight.
Bar plots are terrible. Why? Simple. They don’t show what your data looks like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Plot 3: Base pair resolution NGS (exome) coverage plots - Part 2</title>
      <link>/./post/let-s-plot-3-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/let-s-plot-3-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Call mosdepth on bam to calculate bp-specific read depth Intersect base pair depth info with transcript and exon number Now it’s R time! Prepare Metadata Load mosdepth / bedtools intersect data and prep Plot Maker, version 1 Version 2 sessionInfo()    Introduction This is a barebones (but detailed enough, I hope) discussion of how to take a bam file, extract base pair resolution coverage data, then finagle the data into coverage plots by gene and exon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Plot 3: Base pair resolution NGS coverage plots (Part I)</title>
      <link>/./post/let-s-plot-3-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/let-s-plot-3-part-i/</guid>
      <description>Load data Curious? Data How many genes are in this dataset? What genes are in here? How many data points (bases) per gene? How many exons per gene? How many base pairs of ABCA4 (well, ABCA4 exons) is covered by more than 10 reads? 5 reads? Let’s check all of the genes to see which are the worst covered We can visually display the data, also Hard to see what is going on, let’s make little plots for each gene Where are genes poorly covered?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Split VCF into n pieces by coordinate</title>
      <link>/./post/split-vcf-into-n-pieces-by-coordinate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/split-vcf-into-n-pieces-by-coordinate/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Read in vcf header Parse out chr / contig sizes Split chr above 3e7 base pairs into equal(ish) size pieces print coordinates given a chromosome / contig calculate coordinates print ’em output ’em for python input (Snakemake) rscript Using the script output sessionInfo()   Introduction bcftools view -r 1:40000-50000 vcf.gz will output (to stdout) a vcf containing the header and variants on chromosome 1 between coordinates 40,000 and 50,000 base pairs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Plot 2: Smoothed Lines</title>
      <link>/./post/let-s-plot-2-smoothed-lines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/let-s-plot-2-smoothed-lines/</guid>
      <description>Get data (two xls files) from here: Load data and look at structure (str) Head (first few lines) AUC, N1P1, Latency Summary of eel and cobra AUC What kind of time points or conditions or whatever do we have again? Summary by pig and region Plot AUC by time and region and pig Prettier plot with lines and more formatting N1P1 Plot Latency plot Bonus   Data from Aaron Rising.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Plot 1: Going in circles </title>
      <link>/./post/let-s-plot-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/let-s-plot-1/</guid>
      <description>What is going on? Where to get the code and data? Import data with readxl OK, first let’s remove the notes. However, we aren’t done. The data is “wide” instead of “long” and we have mixed session IDs (Amp 1-3 and Angle 1-3) with the value type. Now we need to extract the session (1,2,3) and the test type (Amp or Angle) Now we have two value types (Angle and Amplitude) in one column.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Let’s Plot?</title>
      <link>/./post/what-is-let-s-plot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/what-is-let-s-plot/</guid>
      <description>Tooling How can I follow along?   The concept is simple - I get data from one of the scientists in my group. Or I get my own. Then I demonstrate, step-by-step, how I generate the plot(s). I’ll also toss in some data science concepts occasionally.
They are a bit sparse on the words because I’m presenting these in person. But I believe they are clear enough for someone to follow along.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>