<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bioinformatics on eye Bioinformatician</title>
    <link>/./categories/bioinformatics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bioinformatics on eye Bioinformatician</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/./categories/bioinformatics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>#GI2019 2019 11 06</title>
      <link>/./post/gi2019-day01/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/gi2019-day01/</guid>
      <description>Genome Informatica 2019 at CSHL
Italics Bold is the speaker
349 attendees. Largest?
189 posters
39 (?) talks
90 countries, 20 (US) states
High(est) % female, URM for gi
Night 1 Comparative 3D genome organization in Apicomplexan parasites Evelien M. Bunnik, Aarthi Venkat, Ferhat Ay, Karine G. Le Roch.
Apicomplexan parasites:
 toxoplasma gondii babesia most prevalent nad morbidity causing pathogens  Try to understand at genomic level
Malaria (plasmodium) genome published 18 years ago</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Developer Portal: eyeIntegration Genesis</title>
      <link>/./post/one-developer-portal-genesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/one-developer-portal-genesis/</guid>
      <description>News! eyeIntegration version 1.0 went live early this year (2019-01-16) and recently was accepted for publication in IOVS. In celebration of the news, I’m posting a small series of posts about the genesis, development, upgrades, and future of eyeIntegration.
You can find our latest manuscript on bioRxiv. The latest update should go live soon.
 Background eyeIntegration was developed to serve as a quick and easy to use normal gene expression portal in eye tissues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Developer Portal: eyeIntegration Web Optimization</title>
      <link>/./post/one-developer-portal-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/one-developer-portal-optimization/</guid>
      <description>This post is a continuation from here.
Really important stuff I learned to make a performant web site in Shiny After a few months of tinkering I had a working web app on my local computer, which is a 32GB of RAM, 1TB SSD Mac Pro trashcan. All of the data objects were .Rdata, which were load() when the site was initialized. This was fine in the beginning and in fact the shiny site was deployed with this structure in May of 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GI2018 - Day Four</title>
      <link>/./post/gi2018-day-four/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/gi2018-day-four/</guid>
      <description>Variant Discovery and Genome Assembly Melissa Wilson Sayres  Prithika Sritharan (Dicks) Zemin Ning (Durbin)   Variant Discovery and Genome Assembly Melissa Wilson Sayres Sex Differences in Reference Genome Affect Variant Calling and Differential Expression
X and Y homology dotplot
 a few regions of alignment (PAR)  @sexchrlab
doi.org/10.1101/346940
 https://www.biorxiv.org/content/early/2018/07/18/346940 preprint on correct tech biases on sex chr in NGS data infer sex chromosome complement pointing out regions on autosomes with sex chr - like alignment  which is screwing up read balance which presumably could influence variant calling   chrY var calls will have many errors</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GI2018 - Day Three</title>
      <link>/./post/gi2018-day-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/gi2018-day-three/</guid>
      <description>Day 3 Rafael Irizarry Keynote Session 4: Transcriptomics, Alternative Splicing and Gene Predictions Mark Robinson (Robinson) Hagen Tilgner (Tilgner) Nikka Keivanfar (Church, 10X) Koen Van den Berge (Clement) Barbara Englehardt (Englehardt) Jeff Gaither (White) Fiona Dick (Tzoulis)  Epigenetics and non-coding genome Jordana Bell (Bell) Wouter Meuleman (Stamatoyannopoulos) Maša Roller (Flicek) Alexander Suh (Suh) Raquel Garcia-Perez (Juan)    Day 3 Very sparse and poorly written notes covering #GI2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GI2018 - Day Two</title>
      <link>/./post/gi2018-day-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/gi2018-day-two/</guid>
      <description>Day Two Personal and Medical Genomics Katie Pollard Keynote Sri Kosuri (Kosuri) Patrick Brennan (Nationwide Children’s) Kaitlin Samocha (Hurles) Tracy Ballinger (Semple) Lucia Spangenberg (Naya)  Comparative, Evolutionary, Metagenomics Ellen Leffler (Kwiatkowski) Luca Penso-Dolfin (Di Palma) Mario Caccamo (NIAB) Carla Cummins (Flicek)    Day Two  Personal and Medical Genomics Very sparse and poorly written notes covering #GI2018.
Typos everywhere. Things may change dramatically over time as I scan back through notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#GI2018 - Day One</title>
      <link>/./post/gi2018-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/gi2018-day-one/</guid>
      <description>Intro 2018-09-17 Sarah Teichmann (Teichmann Lab) Girgio Gonnella (Stefan Kurtz) Luke Zappia (Oshlack?) Laura Huerta (Papatheodorou) Casey Greene (Greene) Sergei Yakneen   Intro Very sparse and poorly written notes covering #GI2018.
Typos everywhere. Things may change dramatically over time as I scan back through notes.
I’ve tried to respect #notwitter. Will be updated periodically.
Speaker (Lab | Group)
BOLDED is voice
 2018-09-17  Sarah Teichmann (Teichmann Lab) Cell Atlas Technologies and the Maternal-Fetal Interface</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Guide to Gene Name Conversion</title>
      <link>/./post/quick-guide-to-gene-name-conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/quick-guide-to-gene-name-conversion/</guid>
      <description>Background There are several popular naming systems for (human) genes:
RefSeq (NM_000350) Ensembl (ENSG00000198691) HGNC Symbol (ABCA4) Entrez (24)  Given enough time in #bioinformatics, you will have to do every possible combination of conversions.
This post will very briefly explain the most expedient way to automatically convert between these formats with R.
 More exhaustive resources http://crazyhottommy.blogspot.com/2014/09/converting-gene-ids-using-bioconductor.html
https://davetang.org/muse/2013/11/25/thoughts-converting-gene-identifiers/
 Ensembl &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; HGNC &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; Entrez Stephen Turner has built a small set of data frames (well, tibbles) with core information, including transcript &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; gene info.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#BoG18: Talk Notes</title>
      <link>/./post/bog18-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/bog18-notes/</guid>
      <description>Intro Genome Engineering and Genome Editing (Tuesday Night) Jef Boeke Writing Genomes “dark matter” big dna  Greg Findlay (Jay Shendure) Stephen Levene (Andrew Fire) David Truong (Jef Boeke) Feng Zhang Molly Gasperini (Jay Shendure) Eilon Sharon (Hunter Fraser) Luca Pinello  Population Genomics (Wednesday morning) Mattias Joakobsson Jaemin Kim (Elaine Ostrander) Ipsita Agarwal (Molly Przeworski) Amnon Koren Sarah Tishkoff Patrick Albers (Gil McVean) Laura Hayward (Guy Sella)  Functional Genetics and Epigenomics Job Dekker Flora Vaccarino Carninci Johnathan Griffiths (Berthold Gottgens) Emma Farley Jake Yeung (Felix Naef) Minal Caliskan (Casey Brown) Parisa Razaz (Talkwoski)  Evolutionary and Non-human genomics Monica Justice Arang Rhie (Erich Jarvis, Adam Phillippy) Olga Dudchenko (Erez Lieberman Aiden) Kasper Munch Gavin Sherlock Anne Ruxandra Carvunis Elaine Ostrander Bobbie Cansdale (Claire Wade)  Cancer and Medical Genomics Trey Ideker Rajbir Batra (Carlos Caldas) Patrick Short (Matthew Hurles) Max Shen (David Gifford) Sharon Plon (PJ Lupo) Massa Shoura (Andrew Fire) Sidi Chen Marcin Imielinski  Computational Genomics (!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy bam downsampling</title>
      <link>/./post/easy-bam-downsampling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/easy-bam-downsampling/</guid>
      <description>When you have a set of ChIP-seq (like) files, it is sometimes useful to downsample the larger samples to more closely match most of the samples. Tommy Tang goes into more detail in his blog post.
Unfortunately the tool suites I use most for bam files (samtools and picard) only downsample to a percentage. Which isn’t ideal when you want your files to be no more than n reads.
This post is just a slight one-upping of Tommy Tang’s process to easily downsample a bam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are you in genomics and building models? Stop using ROC - use PR</title>
      <link>/./post/are-you-in-genomics-stop-using-roc-use-pr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/are-you-in-genomics-stop-using-roc-use-pr/</guid>
      <description>tldr Area Under the Curve (AUC) of Receiver Operating Characteristic (ROC) is a terrible metric for a genomics problem. Do not use it. This metric also goes by AUC or AUROC. Use Precision Recall AUC.
 Inspiration for this post I am working on a machine learning problem in genomics I was getting really confused why AUROC was so worthless scienceTwitter featuring Anshul Kundaje  I want to save you (some time)   What’s a ROC?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Plot 4: R vs Excel, Round 1</title>
      <link>/./post/let-s-plot-4-r-vs-excel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/let-s-plot-4-r-vs-excel/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Data Cleaning Reformatting Box Plot Boxplot with all the data displayed I used to prefer violin plots I’m a fan of beeswarm plots with boxplots Doing statistics. Session   Introduction The battle that we’ve all been waiting for. Excel vs. R. Bar plot versus a plot that actually shows the data.
Yeah, this isn’t a fair fight.
Bar plots are terrible. Why? Simple. They don’t show what your data looks like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Plot 3: Base pair resolution NGS (exome) coverage plots - Part 2</title>
      <link>/./post/let-s-plot-3-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/let-s-plot-3-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Call mosdepth on bam to calculate bp-specific read depth Intersect base pair depth info with transcript and exon number Now it’s R time! Prepare Metadata Load mosdepth / bedtools intersect data and prep Plot Maker, version 1 Version 2 sessionInfo()    Introduction This is a barebones (but detailed enough, I hope) discussion of how to take a bam file, extract base pair resolution coverage data, then finagle the data into coverage plots by gene and exon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Plot 3: Base pair resolution NGS coverage plots (Part I)</title>
      <link>/./post/let-s-plot-3-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/let-s-plot-3-part-i/</guid>
      <description>Load data Curious? Data How many genes are in this dataset? What genes are in here? How many data points (bases) per gene? How many exons per gene? How many base pairs of ABCA4 (well, ABCA4 exons) is covered by more than 10 reads? 5 reads? Let’s check all of the genes to see which are the worst covered We can visually display the data, also Hard to see what is going on, let’s make little plots for each gene Where are genes poorly covered?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Split VCF into n pieces by coordinate</title>
      <link>/./post/split-vcf-into-n-pieces-by-coordinate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/split-vcf-into-n-pieces-by-coordinate/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Read in vcf header Parse out chr / contig sizes Split chr above 3e7 base pairs into equal(ish) size pieces print coordinates given a chromosome / contig calculate coordinates print ’em output ’em for python input (Snakemake) rscript Using the script output sessionInfo()   Introduction bcftools view -r 1:40000-50000 vcf.gz will output (to stdout) a vcf containing the header and variants on chromosome 1 between coordinates 40,000 and 50,000 base pairs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>